<Document>
 # Weapons and alert levels

  ## Foreword
  While firearms of all varieties are incredibly common across known-space, the NanoTrasen Corporation does not permit
  individuals without proper licenses to carry weapons onboard its stations. [color=#a40000]Carrying any weapon on NanoTrasen property
  without proper authorization is a crime.[/color]

  ## Armament escalation

  ## Loadout weapons
  Weapons obtainable in the loadout menu can always be open carried with an exception to the head of security.
  The HOS is only allowed to visibly carry the energy shotgun on a code green or blue.
  On code green weapons like the c20 and wt550 must be put in a bag or something similar to be concealed.

  ## Alert level escalation
  On code green and above The HOS and Warden can visibly carry any weaponry they see fit inside the brig. Or a longarm with non-lethal ammunition outside the brig.

  Code Green: Security and Command are only permitted to visibly carry small firearms like pistols, lethal rounds permitted. (CCO may carry a chester if loaded with non-lethal rounds)
  The default code when no threats are present. Code greens are usually calm and easy shifts.

  Code Blue: Security and Command are permitted to TEMPORARILY carry longer arms and rifles including lethal ammunitions at the discretion of the HOS and warden for certain missions or events. Avoid excessive arming.
  The code when there are signs of hostile activity, whether it is from alien lifeforms or syndicate traitors within the crew. After the event is over with longarm weapons are returned to armory again while the station remains on code blue.

  Code Red and worse: Security and Commmand are expected to carry heavy weaponry to keep the crew safe. On code red the crew (only crew, not non-crew) may be armed at the discretion of command.
  The code when the station is facing extreme danger or has a real shortage of command and security, the crew is suggested to move together and request arms from security if they think it is necessary.

  Code Epsilon for incoming death squad, any and all means can be used to repell against the death squad. Hand out the best command gear to yourselves or crew and win.

  Salvagers are allowed to carry special salvager weapons which are special weaponry made for just salvage specialists. Underpowered firearms like ancient weak rifles and pistols could be permitted by command at their discretion.
</Document>
